妈 你别紧张好吗?
Mom, would you relax?
那里离这有十条街远
That was 10 blocks from here,
而且那女的是晚上自己一个人走
and the woman was walking alone at night.
我从来不会那样做
I would never do that.
妈 拜托 别担心了
Mom, come on, stop worrying.
这条街很安全 这楼也很安全 没什么
This is a safe street. This is a safe building. There's nothing...Aah!
哦 天啊 你飞进来干什么
Oh, my God! What are you doing in here?
妈 我得挂了 我得挂了
Mom, I gotta go. I gotta go.
天啊
Oh, my God.
没关系 你只管看报纸
That's fine, you just read the paper.
我去拿个锅
I'm gonna get a pot.
不是给你用的
It's not for you.
没问题 很好
Okay, that's fine.
看家庭马戏团的漫画
Read the Family Circus...
享受温馨的喜剧
enjoy the gentle comedy...
哦 天呐 天呐 天呐
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
哦 哦 哦 天呐
Ugh. Oh, God. Oh, God.
门没关
It's open, you guys.
嗨      嗨 有什么事吗?
Hi.        Hi. Can I help you?
我找菲比 她还住在这里吗?
I'm looking for Phoebe, does she still live here?
她不住这了 但我可以给她传个信息
Uh, no, she doesn't. But I can get a message to her
太棒了! 就跟她说 她的老公来过
Great. Uh, just tell her her husband stopped by.
她的什么?
Her what? Aah!
嘿 你怎么办到的?
Hey, how did you do that?
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧
《老友记》蓝光版 第02季 第04集
菲比的老公  The One With Phoebe's Husband
调校制作：海盗美剧 寒 枫
字幕编辑：海盗美剧 悠悠慕雪
这太扯了 菲比 你怎么结婚了?
This is unbelievable, Pheebs. How can you be married?
我不是那种"结婚"的结婚
Well, I mean, I'm not "married" married, you know?
他只是个朋友 他是同性恋
He was just a friend, and he's gay
他是加拿大人 只是需要绿卡
and he was from Canada, and he just needed a green card.
我真不敢相信你嫁给了邓肯
I can't believe you married Duncan.
你怎么不告诉我呢?
I mean, how could you not tell me?
我们住在一起 我们告诉彼此任何事
We lived together, we told each other everything.
对不起 摩妮卡 但如果我跟你说 你就会批评我
I'm sorry, Monica, but I knew if I told you, you'd get really, like, judgmental
也不会赞成我      我当然不会赞成
and would not approve.        Of course I wouldn't approve.
你深深的爱着那个同性恋 你到底在想什么啊?
I mean, you were totally in love with this guy who, hello was gay. I mean, what the hell were you thinking?
看? 你还以为她只是批评
See? And you thought she'd be judgmental.
我不爱他 我只是帮一个朋友
Okay, I wasn't in love with him. And I was just helping out a friend.
拜托 他离开后你一个月没下床
Please. When he left town you stayed in your pajamas for a month.
而且我还看到你吃了一个起司汉堡
And I saw you eat a cheeseburger.
难道没有吗?
Well, didn't you?
可能有吧
I might have.
真不敢相信你不告诉我
I can't believe you didn't tell me.
难道你告诉了我一切事情么?
Come on. Like you tell me everything?
我有什么没告诉你么?
What have I not told you?
我不知道 额
Ooh, I don't know. Urn...
比如说外面电线杆上的内衣是你的
How about the fact that the underwear out there on the telephone pole is yours
是你和搞笑巴比在阳台上做爱时丢下去的
from when you were having sex with Fun Bobby on the terrace.
什么?      等等 谁告诉你的?
What?        Wait a minute. Who told you?
你死定了
You are dead meat.
我不知道那是个大秘密
I didn't know it was a big secret.
哦 没什么大不了 一点关系也没有
Oh, it's not big. Not at all.
那就像 比如说
You know kind of on the same lines as, say,
我不知道...有人有第三个乳头一样
I don't know, having a third nipple.
你有三个乳头?
You have a third nipple?
你这贱人!
You bitch.
秀一秀!秀一秀!
Whip it out. Whip it out.
没什么好看的 只是很小的突起 完全没有用处
No, come on. There's nothing to see. It's just a tiny bump. It's totally useless.
难道你其他的乳头是多功能的?
Oh, as opposed to your other multifunctional nipples?
真不敢相信你 你跟我说那只是个小包
I can't believe you. You told me it was a nubbin.
乔伊 你以为小包是什么样子?
Joey, what did you think a nubbin was?
我不知道 你看到什么东西
I don't know. You see something,
然后听到一个词 我就以为是那样了
you hear a word, I thought that's what it was.
让我再看一次      秀一下你的小包
Let me see it again.        Yeah, show us your nubbin.
乔伊演过色情片
Joey was in a porno movie.
如果我死 我也要拖大家下水
If I'm going down, I'm taking everybody with me.
天呐 你演过色情片?
Oh, my God. You were in a porno?
好啦 好啦 那时我还年轻 只想要份工作
All right, all right. I was young and I just wanted a job, okay?
但最后一刻我没法做下去
But at the last minute I couldn't go through with it.
所以他们就让我演修影印机的人 但我没法修
So they let me be the guy who comes in to fix the copier but can't
因为有人在上面做爱
because there's people having sex on it.
哇哦
Wow.
真狂野!
That is wild.
那是什么形状?      有长毛吗?
So, what's it shaped like?        Is there a hair on it?
你弹它时会有什么反应?
What happens if you flick it?
额 它有什么特殊之处?
So, uh, does it do anything, you know, special?
按下我的第三个乳头可以通往
Why yes, Ross, pressing my third nipple opens the delivery entrance
纳尼亚的神奇国度
to the magical land of Narnia.
你们知道么 有些文化里
You know, in some cultures,
第三个乳头象征着男性雄风
having a third nipple is actually a sign of virility.
你可以住最好的地方 还有裸女围着你跳舞
You get the best huts, and women dance naked around you.
哈 这些文化 有没有可能恰巧在美国中部?
Huh. Are, uh, any of these cultures, per chance, in the Tri-State area?
你太厉害了 有什么是你不知道的吗?
You know, you are so amazing. Is there anything you don't know?
哦 "茱莉好聪明"  "茱莉好特别!"
Ooh. Julie's so smart. Julie's so special.
亲爱的 我跟你一样希望你和罗斯复合
Look, honey, I wanted you to hook up with Ross as much as you did.
但他现在有她了 你必须忘了他
But he's with her now. You're just gonna have to get over it.
哦 我必须得忘了他
Oh, I'm going to have to get over it.
我都不知道该怎么办 原来我只要忘了他就好了
God see I didn't know that's what I had to do. I just have to get over it.
漂亮小姐!      你要去哪?
Sassy lady.       Where are you going?
我要去见邓肯 他今晚在花园广场溜冰
Urn, I'm gonna go meet Duncan. He's skating tonight at the Garden.
他是冰上剧团的
He's in the Capades.
冰上溜冰?      不 不 在柏油路上溜
The Ice Capades?        No, no, the Gravel Capades.
转弯不会很快 但史努比跌倒时 非常好笑
Yeah the turns aren't as fast, but when Snoopy falls? Funny.
真不敢相信你竟然为他打扮 你这是在重蹈覆辙
I can't believe you're dressing up for him. I mean, you're just, you're setting yourself up all over again.
不是的
Okay, no.
我告诉你 我见他就是为了能彻底忘了他
For your information, I'm going to see him so I can put all those feelings behind me.
我这样打扮是因为我觉得这样很好
And the reason I'm dressed like this is because I think it's nice
为同性恋老公打扮
to look nice for your gay husband.
该死 牛奶没了
Darn it, we're all out of milk.
钱德 帮我加点好吗?
Hey, Chandler, will you fill me up here?
哦 我懂了 原来是因为我有第三个乳头
Oh, I see, I see. Because of the third nipple thing.
亲爱的 晚点见      再见
Okay, sweetie, I'll see you later.        Bye.
瑞秋 待会儿见      拜拜 茱莉
See you later, Rach.        Byebye, Julie.
嗨      嗨
Hey.        Hey.
拜托 别闹了
Hey, come on, cut it out.
嗨      什么事?
Hey.        What?
我能问你一件事吗?      当然可以
Can I ask you something?        Sure.
什么?
What?
快点 跟我说说      好吧
Come on. Talk to me.        Okay.
你恋爱时 花的最久时间
What's the longest you've been in a relationship before
在发生关系之前?
having, having, having the sex?
什么? 谁没有? 你跟茱莉还没有?
Why? Who's not? Are you and Julie not?
你跟茱莉还没上床吗?
Are you and Julie not having sex?
额
Well
技术上来说?
Technically?
没有      哇哦
No.        Wow.
是因为她在床上很冷淡吗?
Is, is it because she's so cold in bed?
还是她有点挑剔 让你感觉像是在学校?
Or is it because she's kind of bossy, makes it feel like school?
不! 她很好 我们不是什么都没做
No. No. She's great. And it's not like we haven't done anything.
我们做了很多其他的事 很多事 比如...
I mean, we do plenty of other stuff. Lots of other stuff like...
不 不! 我不需要知道细节
no, no. Don't need to know the details.
不 只是...
No. It's just...
是我的原因
It's me.
我这辈子就只跟过一个女人
You know, I've only been with one woman my whole life
结果她变成一个同性恋
and she turned out to be a lesbian.
所以现在我很害怕
So now I've got myself all psyched out.
这就像是...
It's become like, this...
这件事...我...
this thing, and I...
你一定觉得我很怪
You must just think I'm weird.
不不不不 我不觉得很怪
No. No, no, no. I don't think it's weird.
我认为 我想 事实上
I think, I think, urn, in fact
事实上 你知道我怎么想吗?      怎么想?
In fact, you know what I think?        What?
我认为这很性感
I think it's sexy.
性感?
Sexy?
我告诉你 作为女人 没有任何事情比
Let me tell you something. As a woman, there is nothing sexier
让男人不想上床更性感
than a man who does not want to have sex.
别开玩笑了      是的 你知道我会怎么做吗?
No kidding.        Oh, yeah. In fact, you know what I'd do?
怎么做?      我会等待
What?        I'd wait.
你会等待?      没错 我会等待
You'd wait?        Yes, absolutely. I would wait
等待
and wait
然后再等下去
Then I'd wait some more.
真的?      没错
Really?        Oh, yeah.
不管她说她有多想要 她怎么乞求你
I don't care how much she tells you she wants it, I don't care if she begs
她说她要和别的男人做爱
she pleads, she tells you she's gonna have sex with another man.
那只表示收到效果了
That just means it's working.
女人真的想要这个?
Women really want this?
比珠宝还渴望
More than jewelry.
嗨
Hi.
菲比!
Phoebe.
嗨
Hi.
看看你! 你看起来真棒
Ah, look at you. You look great.
是吗? 谢谢
Do I? Thank you.
你也是 闪闪发光      谢谢
So do you. Sparkly.        Thanks.
那么...
So...
这真是太棒了 溜冰男主角
Wow. This is pretty wonderful, huh, Mr. Major Capades Guy.
我还记得你以前只是个跑龙套的
I remember when you were just like King Friday in Mr. Roger's Ice Is Nice.
你总是说我会成功的
You always said I'd make it.
是啊 我总是有这方面的怪才能
Yeah, well, you know, I'm kind of spooky that way. Woo.
天啊 我好想你
God, I missed you.
我得去换件衣服      好的
I'm gonna get changed.        Okay.
额 我是说现在
Urn, now.
什么?      菲比
What?        Pheebs.
哦 好的
Oh. Right. Okay.
什么?
What?
斗牛士
The Matador so
亲爱的 帮我拿一下好吗?      当然
Sweetie, can you hold this for a second?        Sure.
谢了
Thanks.
茱莉?      嗯?
Uh, Julie?        Yeah.
对不起 你脸上有个古生物学家
Sorry, you had a paleontologist on your face.
但是现在没了 你没事了
But, uh, it's gone now. You're all right.
大家好      嗨
Hi, everyone.        Hi.
听着 听着 我要谢谢你之前跟我的聊天
Oh, listen, listen...I wanted to thank you for, uh, our little talk before.
哦不客气 所以你会等下去么?
Oh, God, no problem. So you're gonna go with the waiting thing?
我本想这么做 但跟你谈过后 我又跟乔伊谈了
Well, I was going to, but after I talked to you, I talked to Joey.
那很好 他怎么说?
Good. Ahem. What did he say?
基本上 他告诉我别想太多 去做就好了
Basically, he told me to get over myself and just do it.
于是我想了想你说的和他说的
So I thought about what you said and thought about what he said.
照他的说法 我今晚就可以和她上床 所以
And, well, his way, I get to have sex tonight, so
我口袋里的是什么?
What is this in my pocket?
天啊 是乔伊的色情片
Why, it's Joey's porno movie.
放进去播吧
Pop it in.
我无所谓
I'm fine with it,
只要你们愿意看里面全是只有两个乳头的人
I mean, if you're okay watching a video, filled with two nippled people.
太棒了 大家都在做爱 那正是我想看的
Great. People having sex. That's just what I need to see.
做爱有什么不对?
What's wrong with people having sex?
嗯...
Well...
你知道 这种片子很冒犯人
Well, urn, you know, these movies are offensive
侮辱女性
and, uh, degrading to women
和女性
and females
灯光总是很呆板
And, uh, the lightings always unflattering.
还有...
And...
摩妮卡 帮我一下啊      管他的 我想看乔伊!
Monica, help me out here.        Hell I wanna see Joey.
这是有故事情节的 还是他们直接就开始做
So is there, like, a story, or do they just start doing it right
当我没说
Oh. Never mind.
等等 那是我见过最疯狂的打字测试
Okay, now, wait a minute. That is the craziest typing test I've ever seen.
我只能说 她最好能得到这份工作
All I say is, she better get the job.
依我看 是他被"聘用"了
Looks to me like he's the one getting the job.
我来了 我来了
Shh. Hey, here I come. Here I come.
我来修影印机了
See I'm coming to fix the copier
我没办法走到影印机那 我心想"我该怎么办"
I can't get to the copier. I'm thinking, "What do I do? What do I do?"
于是我就看着他们做爱
So I just watch them have sex.
然后我要说台词了
And then I say. Wait, here's my line.
那样对进纸盒不好
You know, that's bad for the paper tray.
干得好 朋友      谢谢
Nice work, my friend.        Thank you.
等等 我又出现了 等等 那家伙的屁股把我挡住了
Wait wait wait, you see me again. Hang on, the guy's butt's blocking me.
我出现了...出现了...出现了...
There I am. There I am. There I am.
额 有什么事吗? 你昨天去找我
So, urn...So, what's up? You came to see me yesterday.
哦 对 额
Oh, yeah, urn...
好吧
All right.
我需要离婚
I kind of need a divorce.
好的
Okay.
怎么了?
How come?
其实我又要结婚了
Urn, actually, I'm getting married again.
什么?      天啊 我真不知道该怎么告诉你
What?        Oh God I don't know how to tell you this.
我是异性恋
I'm straight.
我知道
Yeah. I know.
我不懂 我不懂 你怎么会是异性恋?
I don't understand. I don't understand. How can you be straight?
你是如此聪明和风趣 又那么会办奥斯卡金奖派对
I mean, you're so smart and funny, and you throw such great Academy Award parties.
我知道 我也是一直那样告诉自己的
I know. That's what I kept telling myself.
但到了某个程度 你再也无法活在谎言里
But you just reach a point where you can't live a lie anymore.
那你知道多久了?
So how long have you known?
我想在某个程度上 我一直知道自己是异性恋
I guess on some level I always knew I was straight.
我以为自己不是
I thought I was supposed to be something else.
我是冰上舞者
You know, I'm an ice dancer,
我所有的朋友都是同性恋 我只是想融入他们
all my friends are gay. I was just trying to fit in.
额
And, urn.
那你真的爱上了一个女人?
And there's actually a woman?
她叫黛柏拉
Her name's Debra.
那她是你第一个女人么?
Well is she the first that you've been with?
我从没告诉过你...
Well I've never told you this...
但我大学时曾经有一 两次
but there were one or two times back in college
喝得醉醺醺的跑去单身酒吧
when I'd get really drunk and go to a straight bar,
醒来发现身旁躺着女人
and wake up with a woman next to me.
我告诉自己那是酒精的缘故
But I told myself it was the liquor
大学每个人都在摸索体验
and everyone experiments in college.
当然
Sure.
现在我知道自己没有选择 我生来就是如此
But now I know I don't have a choice about this. I was born this way.
我不知道要说什么
I don't know what to say.
你和一个人结婚六年 以为自己很了解他
I mean, you know, you're married to someone for six years, and you think you know him.
但有一天他突然说"哦!我不是同性恋
And then one day he says, "Oh, I'm not gay."
我还是我啊
I'm, I'm still me.
你为什么在六年前没发现这件事呢?
Why couldn't you just have figured this out six years ago?
里面闻起来还是有猴子的味道
You know, it still smells like monkey in there.
我们又有话可聊了
Well, that saves us the conversation.
今晚很棒 但我好累
Well, this has been great, but I'm officially wiped.
我也是 我们该走了      不
Me too. We should get going.        No.
不!拜托
No. I mean. No. Come on, you guys.
别这样 看 现在才十一点半
Come on, look, it's only 11:30.
我们来聊天 我们好久没一起聊天了
Let's just talk. We never just hang out and talk anymore.
瑞秋 我们总在一起聊天
Rachel, that's all we do.
我们或许经常那样 但茱莉呢?
Maybe that's all we do. What about Julie?
茱莉怎样?
What about Julie?
你加入我们将近两个月了
Well, you have been in our lives for nearly two months now
但我们并不真的了解你
and we don't really know you.
我是说 茱莉是谁? 你喜欢什么? 讨厌什么?
I mean, who is Julie? I mean, what do you like? What don't you like?
我们想知道一切
We want to know everything.
那要花点时间
Well, heh, that could take a while.
所以呢?
So?
这里有谁没时间了解茱莉?
I mean who here does not have the time to get to know Julie?
我有时问      我有
I got the time to get to know Julie.        I got time, yeah.
瑞秋 额 我很了解她 我可以走吗?
Uh, Rach, ahem, I know her pretty well. Can I go?
好吧
That's fine.
我们从你的童年开始吧 你的童年如何?
Okay, Julie, so let's start with your childhood. What was that like?
简而言之
Well in a nut shell
那你告诉你父母了吗?
So, urn, have you told your parents?
还没 但那没问题 他们都很好
No, but it'll be okay. They're pretty cool.
我哥也是异性恋 所以...
My brother's straight, so...
好了
Here you go.
对了 我还有个问题
You know what? I just have one more question. Urn...
如果你早点发现 而我又在你身边
If you had figured this out sooner and, urn, I had been around
你觉得我会不会是...?
do you think I would have been the one who...?
不 不 别告诉我
No, no. That's all right. Don't tell me.
不管是哪个答案都不会让我好过些 拿去吧
I don't think either answer would make me feel better. Here.
我爱你 菲比
I love you, Phoebe.
所以你哥是异性恋 是吗?
So your brother's straight, huh?
我是认真的
Seriously.
我二年级的老师是汤姆斯小姐
And my second grade teacher was Miss Thomas
一年级老师是柯比太太
and my first grade teacher was Mrs. Cobb.
额 葛比太太?
Ahem. Mrs. Gobb?
不 柯比 柯比沙拉的柯比
No, Cobb. Like cobb salad.
哦好
Hmm, okay.
那 柯比沙拉里面到底有什么?
Now, what exactly is in a cobb salad?
我要回家了
I'm going home.
天啊 茱莉还真能聊
Boy, that Julie's a talker, huh?
晚安
Good night.
那么     晚安
So...        Good night.
时候不早了 你或许不打算...
It's pretty late. You're probably, uh, not still planning on...
不 我还是想
Oh. No, no, I am.
你紧张吗?
Well, hey, are you nervous?
不不 我 额
No no. I, uh
我以前做过
I have done it before.
我是说 你打算怎么做?
Well, okay I mean how are you gonna handle it?
你会先跟她谈一谈 或者就直接扑上去?
Are you gonna talk about it before hand? Are you just gonna pounce?
我不知道 我想我就...
I, uh I don't know. I guess I'm just gonna...
顺其自然
see, see what happens.
好吧 祝你好运
Okay. Good luck.
怎么了?
What? Uh...
怎么了?      没什么
What?        Nothing. I mean, urn...
这是你和她的第一次 你也知道
It is your first time with her, and, you know,
如果第一次不顺利的话...
if the first time doesn't go well..
以后再想恢复好就很难了
Well then, that's pretty darn hard to recover from.
额 现在我紧张了
Okay, now I'm nervous.
或许你应该推迟
Maybe you should put it off.
不 我不想延期了
No, no, I don't want to put it off.
我去年一整年都很悲惨
God, I'm just, I spent last year being so unbelievably miserable.
现在我真的很快乐
And now, now I'm actually happy.
真的很快乐
You know I mean, really happy.
我只是不想...
I just don't wanna...
我不想搞砸 你懂吗?
I don't wanna mess it up, you know?
我懂
I know.
对
Yeah.
对不起      不是你的错
I'm sorry.        No, it's not your fault.
是啊
Right.
也许不必这么困难
Maybe it doesn't have to be this tough.
或许你说的"顺其自然"是最好的做法
Maybe you were on the right track with that whole, you know, spontaneous thing.
女人喜欢那样      真的?
I mean women really like that.        Really?
是啊 我是说 如果
Yeah. I mean, you know, if
我是说如果是我的话 我会希望你      什么?
I mean if it were me, I'd, you know, want you to        What?
我也不知道 趁我没防备时给我 就像 一个真正的
I don't know, catch me off guard. You know, with, like, a really...
很棒的吻
good kiss.
就是
You know, really...
刚开始是轻柔的吻
sort of, urn, soft at first.
然后拨开我脸上的头发
And then maybe, urn, brush the hair away from my face.
然后深情的看着我的眼睛
And then look far into my eyes
让我知道有件
in a way that let me know something
非常美妙的事情就要发生
amazing is about to happen.
然后 我不知道...然后
And then, I don't know, then...
你会把我拉得更紧
you'd pull me really close to you so that
那样我就紧紧贴着你
So that I'd be pressed up, you know, right against you.
那样就会有种...
And, urn, it would get kind of...
汗涔涔
sweaty...
朦朦胧胧的感觉
and, uh. And blurry
于是就这样自然而然发生了
And then it's just happening.
谢了 瑞秋 晚安
Thanks, Rach. Good night.
哦 天啊!
Oh, God.
早安!
Good morning.
昨晚有人爽到了
Well, somebody got some last night.
两次!
Twice.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧